等一下
Hold on a second.
好球
Nice, nice.
有东西给你
I got somethin' for you.
这是什么
What's this?
812块
Eight hundred and twelve bucks.
我不知道大李昂怎么跟你说的
I don't know what Big Leon told ya,
跟我过夜得凑够一千才行
but it's an even thousand if you want me for the whole night.
这是要干什么
What's this for?
我现在赚钱了
Well, I'm making money now.
这是要还你帮我付的大头照费用
and this is payin' you back for head shots,
电费跟数不清的披萨钱
electric bills, and so many slices of pizza I can't even count.
我爱你
I love you, man.
谢了  老兄  我有钱可以买小马了
Well, thanks, man. Now I can get my pony.
这是我一点心意
This is a little extra something for...
谢谢你一直以来对我的关照
...always being there for me.
我不知道该说什么了
Wow, I don't know what to say.
-怎么样  -不知道
- What do you say? - I don't know.
这是个手镯吧
It's a bracelet.
是吧  上头还刻了字  你看看
Isn't it? It's engraved, too. Check it out.
"我的好兄弟"
"To my best bud."
谢了  好兄弟
Thanks, best bud.
戴上啊
Put it on.
现在吗
Now?
不  这么贵重的东西应该留到特殊的场合再戴
No, it should be saved for a special occasion.
不  妙就妙在这里  这配什么都好看
No, that's the beauty part. It goes with everything.
你戴起来光鲜亮丽
When you put this on, you're good to go.
天啊
Oh, man!
真是太配你了
You are so wearing that bracelet!
可不是嘛
I so am!
你知道这对你的性生活有什么样的影响吗
You have any idea what this'll do for your sex life?
刚开始时说不定会让我慢半拍
It might slow down at first, but...
等到习惯这个重量之后  我就会重振雄风了
...once I'm used to the extra weight, I'll be back on track.
-看起来很好  -那就好
- This all looks good. - Great.
如果我要打电话询问你以前的经验呢
And if I want to call for a reference on your last job?
就写在下面  我经理叫钱德勒·宾
That's there, on the bottom, see? The manager, Chandler Bing?
好吧
All right.
看看你是不是有真材实料
Let's see if you're as good in person as you are on paper.
试做一份沙拉
Make me a salad.
沙拉  其实我可以做些难度比较高的
A salad? Really I, I could do something a little more complicated if you like.
不用  沙拉就行了
No, just the salad will be fine.
没问题
You got it.
我要你一边做  一边告诉我的进度
Now I want you to tell me what you're doing while you're doing it.
好  我在撕生菜
All right. Well, I'm tearing the lettuce.
菜脏吗
Is it dirty?
不  别担心  我会清洗
Oh, no, no. I'm gonna wash it.
别洗  我喜欢脏的
Don't. I like it dirty.
悉听尊便
That's your call.
好  你接下来要做什么
So, what are you going to do next?
我想  我接下来要切番茄了
I thought that I'd cut up the tomatoes.
番茄结实吗
Are they firm?
还可以吧
They're all right.
确定没坏吗
You sure they haven't gone bad?
确定没非常  非常坏吗
You sure they're not very, very bad?
没  真的  还好
No, really, they're okay.
你会切得很漂亮吗
You gonna slice them up real nice?
事实上  我打算切丝
Actually, I was gonna do them julienne.
我走了
I'm out of here!
喂
Hello?
不  瑞秋现在不在  你要不要留话
No, Rachel's not here. Can I take a message?
好  凯西怎么个拼法
Alright, and how do we spell Casey?
打棒球那个  还是合唱团那个
Is it like "at the Bat" or "and the Sunshine Band"?
好  再见
OK, bye-bye.
这个凯西是谁
Hey, who's this Casey?
她看电影认识的人
Some guy she met at the movies.
是吗  他找她干什么
Really? What does he want with her?
我猜他想跟她跳点小舞
I guess he wants to do a little dance...
做点小爱
...you know, make a little love....
也许今晚就能推倒她
Well, pretty much get down tonight.
我不知道  我不懂
I don't know. I don't get...
我不懂  两个月前  我们就差这么一丁点
I don't get it! Two months ago, Rachel and I were this close.
现在呢  我在替她看电影认识的人留言
Now I'm taking messages from guys she meets at the movies?
应该是这个凯西替我留言才对
I mean, this Casey should be taking down my messages, you know?
要么我跟瑞秋应该在一起
Or Rachel and I should be together...
然后我们订个自助语音服务
...and we should get some kind of message service.
耐心点  会有那一天的
Hang in there. It's gonna happen.
好  你怎么知道的
OK, now how do you know that?
因为她是你的龙虾
Because she's your lobster.
她这话有内涵
Oh, she's going somewhere.
谁不晓得  龙虾一旦恋爱  就会白头偕老
C'mon you guys. It's a known fact that lobsters fall in love and mate for life.
你真的可以看到老龙虾夫妻
You know what? You can actually see old lobster couples...
爪牵着爪  在水缸里散步
...walking around their tank, holding claws, like....
好点了吗
Hey, you feeling better?
我想这第五个澡应该把我面试的阴影给洗掉了
Yeah, I think that fifth shower got the interview off me.
还有其它可能性吗
Do you have other possibilities?
有  有可能我会交不上房租
Yeah. There is the possibility that I won't make rent.
摩妮卡  需要的话  我可以借你点钱
Monica, if you want, I can lend you some money.
不用  如果我没有办法马上还
No no no, if I couldn't pay you back right away
我看到你就会紧张内疚
then I'd feel guilty and tense every time I saw you.
那你要不跟爸妈借吧
Then why not borrow it from Mom and Dad?
反正你看到他们本来就会紧张内疚
You feel guilty and tense around them already.
还不如趁机会跟他们刮点钱
Might as well make some money off of them.
他说得很有道理
The man's got a point.
那个闪闪发光的是什么东西
What is that sparkly thing?
那个是...
That thing, it's a uhh. . .
对  是有点俗气
Yeah, it's a little flashy.
没有
No, no.
才不会  对道上兄弟来讲不可不俗气
No, no. It's not flashy. Not for a goodfella.
真够犀利的
Man, that is sharp!
你一定花了不少达布隆金币吧
That must have cost you quite a few doubloons.
亲爱的
Hi, darling.
这是什么
What's this?
你以前的东西
Some of your old stuff.
亲爱的  我们要给你一个惊喜
Well, sweetie, we have a surprise for you.
你房间要改成健身房了
We're turning your room into a gym.
的确是个惊喜
Wow, that is a surprise!
只有个小问题  怎么不挑罗斯的房间
Just one question. Why not Ross's room?
天呐  那我们也讨论过了
Gosh. We talked about that...
但你哥有那么多的科学奖杯  奖牌  勋章...
... but your brother had so many science trophies, plaques, merit badges....
我们不想去惊动它们
We didn't want to disturb them.
天理不容
God forbid!
瑞秋
Oh, hi Rachel.
听说你父母分开了  真是遗憾
Oh, we were so sorry to hear about your parents splitting up, dear.
他们只是分居  谁知道呢  看看吧
Well, they're just separated. You never know! We'll see.
老实说  我们一点也不惊讶
I can't say any of us were surprised.
从我们认识他们开始  他们就一直很不快乐
Your parents've been unhappy ever since we've known them.
特别是在夏威夷那件事之后
Especially after that incident in Hawaii.
什么  哪件事啊
What? What incident?
没什么  一定是我记错人了
No, no. I must be thinking of someone else.
可能是我
Maybe me!
你不是要叠衣服吗  快去吧  亲爱的
Don't you have some folding to do? Go fold, dear.
快  去叠衣服
Fold. You fold.
-还要再加一点吗  -不用了  谢谢
- Do you want a refill? - No, I'm all right, thanks.
等我一下  我要学得逼真一点
OK, you gotta give me a second, I wanna get this just right.
老兄  十一点方向  有个辣妹在看着你
Dude, eleven o'clock, totally hot babe checking you out.
感觉真好  我可以去装个鸡鸡了
That was really good. I think I'm ready for my penis now.
我知道你在想  戴夫·托马斯  温蒂汉堡的创办人
I know what you're thinking. Dave Thomas, founder of Wendy's.
-我叫盖尔  -我是钱德勒
- I'm Gail. - Chandler.
我真得走了  很高兴认识你
I, I really have to be somewhere but it was nice meeting you.
怎么回事
What?
真是太好了
Oh this is excellent.
他可以送我录像机  也可以送我一套高尔夫球杆
You know he coulda gotten me a VCR, he coulda gotten me a set of golf clubs,
但没有  他送了我一个女人驱赶器
but no, he has to get me the woman repeller,
简直就是眼中钉  肉中刺
The eyesore from the Liberace House of Crap!
-不至于吧  -说得轻巧
- It's not bad. - Oh, yeah, easy for you to say.
你又没到处炫耀"怪头先生"丢掉的破烂
You're not sporting a reject from the Mr. T collection!
钱德勒  钱德勒
Chandler, Chandler.
"我可怜戴着我首饰的傻蛋  可怜他  可怜他"
"I pity the fool that puts on my jewelry! I do! I do!"
"我可怜戴着"
"I pity that fool"
兄弟  我们正在玩名人模仿秀呢
Hey, man! We were just doing some impressions over here.
你来一段马塞尔·马索的哑剧
Do your Marcel Marceau.
他表演得还真不错
That's actually good.
你看看那个家伙
Would you look at that guy?
他跟她都聊了多久了
How long has he been talking to her?
滚开  兄弟  她只是服务生  又不是艺妓
It's like, back off, buddy! She's a waitress, not a geisha.
我想她不介意
I think she's okay.
你看  看看
Look at that, look at that,
你看她把他推开  他还不滚
see how she's pushing him away and he won't budge!
我不能坐视不管
All right. I'm gonna do something.
我们可以在山上租个公寓
We'll get a condo right on the mountain outside.
滑进滑出  很不错
Ski in, ski out, it's great.
请问  你是瑞秋吗
Excuse me? Are you Rachel?
什么
What?
我叫罗斯·盖勒
Ross Geller.
天呐  你登的广告上说你漂亮  但也太漂亮了吧
God, in your ad you said you were pretty, but wow!
你要干什么
What are you doing?
老天  我记错日期了吗
Oh, my God, is this the wrong day?
我真不敢相信
I don't believe it!
这事如果成了的话  将来跟孙子们就有话讲了
I guess if it works out, we'll, we'll have something to tell the grandkids.
是的
You sure will.
我该走了
I've gotta go.
保重了
Take care.
好  慢走  再见
OK, see ya later, nice meeting you.
不客气
You're welcome.
-什么  -我是在救你
- What? - I was saving you.
不让我跟有趣的男人愉快地交谈  这就算拯救吗
Saving me from a pleasant conversation with an interesting man?
我刚坐在那边看你...
From where I was sitting,
罗斯  听我说
Okay, Ross, listen to me.
我不是要你救的人
I am not yours to save.
你是
But you are.
什么
What?
你是我的龙虾
You're my lobster.
你又在装跟我相亲了吗
O.K. You know what? Are you being the blind-date guy again?
不  你是我的龙虾
No, you're my lobster.
你看  两只龙虾
See, Lobsters....
在水缸里  它们老了...
In the tank, when they're old...
一起爪牵爪散步
...they get with the They walk around holding the claws.
在水缸里
In the tank! You know, with...
爪牵着爪
...with the holding and....
菲比  帮我解释一下龙虾的事  好不好
Pheebs, you wanna help me with the lobster thing?
再表演一次牵爪
Do the claws again.
瑞秋  别管龙虾的事了  好吗
Rach, forget the lobsters, okay?
谈点...  我们俩怎么办
Let's talk... What about us?
罗斯  没有"我们"  好吗
Ross, there is no "us," okay?
-不  可...  -不  你听我说
- No, but... - No! Listen to me!
我爱上了你  然后我受了伤
I fell for you and I get clobbered.
然后你爱上我  结果我还是受伤了
You then fall for me and I again, somehow, get clobbered.
我受够了伤害
I'm tired of being clobbered, you know?
根本就不值得
It's just not worth it.
但是...
Well, but
没有"但是"  罗斯
No "but," Ross.
我们永远不会有结果的  接受吧
We are never gonna happen, okay? Accept that.
除非什么呢
Except that what?
不  不
No. No.
"接受"吧
Accept that.
兄弟  你看  我的好兄弟  你怎么样
Hey, man! Look, it's my best bud! How you doing?
你演马塞尔·马索真是越来越像样了
You're really gettin' good at that Marcel Marceau thing.
我们去打球怎么样  你跟我  怎么样
Hey, listen what do you say uh, we play some ball, you and me, huh, what do you say?
好吧  是我不好
Okay, that's my bad.
你要是那么讨厌那只手镯  直说就可以了
If you hated the bracelet so much, Chandler, you should have just said so
我戴着我这么讨厌的手镯
Well, doesn't the fact that I wore the bracelet even though I hated it
不能证明我多么重视我们之间的友谊吗
say something about our friendship and how much it means to me?
那你侮辱这只手镯  还嘲笑我的那件事呢
Well, what about the fact that you insulted the bracelet and you made fun of me?
就这点上说  我是个混蛋
OK, well that's the part where I'm a wank.
不过我希望你不要纠结这一点
But I was hoping we wouldn't focus on that.
别这样  兄弟  我已经向你道歉一百次了
Come on, man! I said I was sorry like a hundred times,
我保证以后镯不离手
I promise, I will never take it off my...
腕
...wrist.
如果你要待在里面生气的话
But if you want to stay in there and be mad...
那你就待着好了
...you just, you stay in there.
你知道吗
You know what?
我向你下跪了
I am here, on my knees...
我举着这些沙发垫子
... holding up these couch cushions...
表达我对你的歉意  还有悔恨
...as a symbol of my sorrow and regret.
跟古时候的人一样
Much like they did in biblical times.
虽然你现在还很生气
Though you may have the anger now....
那个斯黛菲·格拉芙屁股真翘
You know, that Steffi Graf has quite a tush.
我只是说说而已  就在电视上
I'm just saying! It's right there!
各位
Hey, guys.
亲爱的
Hi, darling.
我孙子呢  你没带过来吗
Where's my grandson, you didn't bring him?
没  他在卡罗尔跟苏珊家里
No, he's at uh, Carol's and Susan's today.
我办公室有一个女的是同志
A woman in my office is a lesbian.
没别的意思
I'm just saying!
杰克  你看  你觉得很好笑的油漆广告来了
Jack, look! There's that house paint commercial that cracks you up!
-你去哪里了 -人间炼狱
- Where have you been? - Emotional hell.
他们有没有借你钱
So, did they lend you the money yet?
没  可能是因为我还没开口
No, but that's probably 'cause I haven't asked them yet.
快去  摩妮卡  去说吧
Come on, Monica, do it.
爸妈
Hey, you guys.
摩妮卡有事要宣布
Monica has some news.
抱歉我以前没告诉你们
So listen, I'm sorry I didn't tell you this before, but...
我现在失业了  我被迫离职了
... I'm no longer at my job. I had to leave it.
为什么
Why?
公司的决定
Because they made me.
你被炒鱿鱼  那你准备怎么办
You were fired? What are you gonna do?
朱迪  放心  这可是我们的小妮妮宝贝
Judy, relax. This is our little Harmonica we're talking about.
我们教导有方
We taught her well.
-薪水的百分之十上哪儿去了  -存银行了
- Ten percent of your paycheck, where does it go? - In the bank.
这就对了  她在吃她的老本  存钱就是应急用的
There you go. So she dips into her savings, that's what it's there for.
她不会有事的
She's gonna be fine.
如果那些钱还不够用的话
And if you need a little extra,
你知道哪里有钱
...you know where to find it.
有面额大一点的吗
Anything larger back there?
真不敢相信
I can't believe it!
别有怨天尤人了好吗
Would you stop already?
别再闷闷不乐了  高兴一点
Get out of the bitter barn and play in the hay.
你说得对  我应该高兴一点
Oh, you're right. I should play in the hay.
忘了我刚才花了四百块
Forget about the fact that I just dropped 400 dollars
去买一个我讨厌的手镯这件事
to replace a bracelet that I hated to begin with.
逗我开心啊
Bring on the hay!
我有个能让你开心起来的东西
I've got something that'll make you happy.
猜甘瑟刚找到什么了
Guess what Gunther found?
你现在有两个了
Hey, now you have two!
Oh, now you have two.
我该怎么办
What am I gonna do?
你怎么有两个
How come you have two?
这个是送你的
This one's for you.
少来了
Get out!
我没办法
No, I can't.
我知道这对你的意义重大
No no, listen, I, I know how much this means to you
我也知道这不只是首饰而已
and I also know that this is about more than just jewelry,
事关你跟我  还有我们是"好兄弟"
It's about you and me and the fact that we're "best buds."
这是友谊的象征吗  我觉得是
Is this friendship? I think so!
快看  我们是手镯兄弟
Check it out! We're bracelet buddies!
大家都会这样叫我们
That's what they'll call us!
好了  拿去吧  什么时候还都可以
Okay, here you go. You can pay me back whenever you like.
你用恐龙支票
You have dinosaur checks?
对啊  你不但能提现  还可以长知识
Yeah, yeah I mean, you get your money and you learn a little something.
这有什么不对的
What's wrong with that?
没什么
Nothing.
你是个小气龙
Hey, you're a cheap-a-saurus!
开玩笑  谢谢  太感谢你了
I'm kidding, I'm kidding. Thank you, I'm very grateful.
摩妮卡  这是什么东西
Hey, Mon, what is this?
我高中时穿的泳衣  我那时体型有点大
That's my bathing suit from high school. I was a little bigger then.
我还以为是给康涅狄格州挡雨用的呢
I thought they used that to cover Connecticut when it rains.
摩妮卡  这带子里有什么
Hey Monica, what's on this video tape?
不知道  问倒我了 放来看看
I don't know. Let's put it in.
这边  杰克  好了
Over here, Jack. Okay.
瑞秋要出来了
I see, Rachel's coming up the path.
是不是很漂亮  杰克
Doesn't she look pretty? Jack?
过来拍她
Can you get this?
我的天
Oh, my God!
你鼻子怎么回事
What is with your nose?
我隔膜长歪了 不得已只好去缩鼻了
They had to reduce it because of my deviated septum.
我错了  那才是用来给康涅狄格州遮雨的
Okay, I was wrong. That's what they use to cover Connecticut.
知道这是什么吗  毕业舞会前的准备
You know what this is, this is us getting ready for the prom.
各位  这没什么好看的
You know what, you guys, we don't have to watch this.
-我们要看  -看嘛  -很有意思
- Yeah, we do. - Come on! - It's fun!
拍摩妮卡
Get a shot of Monica.
摩妮卡在哪里
Where's Monica?
在这里  老爸
Over here, Dad!
等一等  镜头怎么缩小
Wait. How do you zoom out?
拍到了
There she is!
那个女的吃了摩妮卡
Some girl ate Monica!
闭嘴  上镜头会多十磅的
Shut up! The camera adds ten pounds.
那到底有几个镜头在拍你
So how many cameras are actually on you?
你好漂亮
Oh, you look so great!
你也好美
So do you! You look beautiful!
怎么了
What?
倒霉  我的蛋黄酱沾到你身上了
Shoot, I think I got mayonnaise on you.
没关系  只碰到肩膀  没弄到衣服
Oh, that's okay. it's just the shoulder, not my dress.
大家笑一笑
Everybody smile!
爸  关掉啦
Oh, Dad, turn it off!
关了
It is off.
爸  你没关  那红灯亮着
Dad, it is not! What's with the red light?
那表示关了
It's the off light.
好了  罗斯
Right, Ross?
很帅嘛  科特尔先生
Looking good, Mr. Kotter.
-你今天晚上很漂亮  -谢谢
- You look pretty tonight. - Oh, thanks.
你今年夏天要做什么
So, uh, what are you gonna do this summer?
就是在家里待着  玩玩音乐
Oh, you know, I'm just gonna, I'm gonna hang out, work on my music.
我钩子没钩吗  袖子一直掉下来  没办法固定
Is my hook unhooked? These things keep falling down, I can't. . .
我看看  不知道
Let me see. I don't know.
今年夏天你有...
So what are you gonna do...
他们来了
The guys are here!
什么安排
... this summer?
玩玩音乐
Work on your music?
天啊  你们看  是洛伊·顾布里克
Oh, my God! There's Roy Gublik!
洛伊《星球大战》看了317次
You know, Roy saw Star Wars 317 times.
他的名字还上了报
He was in the paper.
奇普呢  他为什么还没来
Where's Chip? Why isn't he here yet?
他会来的  你就放心吧
He'll be here, okay? Take a chill pill.
好了
There.
我刚告诉瑞秋  洛伊摸我的咪咪
I just told Rachel that Roy touched my boob.
没男伴我去不成毕业舞会  来不及了
I can't go to the prom without a date. I can't! It's too late!
你要是不去  我也不去了
If you're not going then I don't want to go either.
我要奇普好看
Oh, I'm gonna kick Chip's ass!
我有个好主意
I have a wonderful idea.
你陪瑞秋去参加舞会
You should take Rachel to the prom.
不太可能
Doubtful.
杰克  那个给我  你跟儿子去谈一谈
Jack, give me that. Talk to your son.
好了  继续  这玩意儿好重
All right, go on. This thing's heavy.
你妈说得对  带她去  穿我的礼服
Your mother's right. Take her. You can wear my tux.
爸  她不会想跟我去的
Dad. She won't wanna go with me.
她当然会  你可是大学生
Of course she would! You're a college man!
-我不知道  -去呀
- I don't know. - Well, come on.
你不想弄清楚吗
Don't you wanna find out?
真不敢相信  我去不成自己的毕业舞会
I can't believe I don't get to go to my own prom!
太残酷了
This is so harsh!
-好  帮我拿着  -乖孩子
- OK. Hold my board. - Thataboy! Thataboy!
好了  各位  我想我们看够了
OK, you guys, ya know, I think we've seen enough
-关了吧  -别别别
- Let's turn it off. - No, no, no.
那好吧  那我就不看了
OK, fine, well I'm not gonna watch, alright.
快  孩子  出发
Come on, kid. Let's go!
-天啊  你真帅  -去给她们看看
- My! Are you handsome! - Let's show them!
等一下  爸
Just a sec, Dad.
冷静  冷静
Okay, be cool. Just be cool.
好了  老爸
Okay, Dad.
瑞秋  准备好了吗  你的白马王子来了
Rachel, ready or not, here comes your knight in shining
糟了
Oh, no.
再见  别等我们回来了
Bye. Don't wait up!
奇普
Chip!
天啊
Oh, dear!
杰克  这个怎么关啊
Jack. How do I turn this off?
按下按钮
Press the button.
哪个  哪个钮  杰克
Which one? Which button? Jack!
那个钮  那个钮
The button! The button!
真不敢相信你那么做了
I can't believe you did that.
是啊
Yeah, well....
瞧  他是她的龙虾
See? He's her lobster!
跟他跳
Dance with him!
妈  我饿了
Mom, I'm hungry!
跟你爸跳
Dance with your father.
我或许不会跳你的霹雳舞
I may not know any of your flash dances
但我也绝不是个盖的
but I'm no slouch on the dance floor.
好吧
All right.
-杰克  -朱迪
- Oh, Jack! - Oh, Judy!